[Music]
foreign
well as promised we have a lot of stocks
to watch out for today so let's get
straight to it our research team is
joining in the sgx50 is not doing much
it's indicating that we may have a quiet
start but there is some news as far as
the windfall taxes concerned so sonal is
joining in uh to appraisers of the
latest so now What's Happening Here uh
well uh the thing that's happened with
respect to windfall tax revision is that
it has been increased on crude oil
production uh from zero to sixty four
hundred rupees and this has happened on
the back of rising crude prices in the
last 15 days that we have seen But the
good news is that export Duty on diesel
has been reduced to nil from 0.5 rupees
per liter earlier and the export Duty on
petrol and ATF continues to be nil now
important to note while increase in
Windfall taxes is negative for oil
producers the likes of ongc in oil India
still they are able to make post tax
realizations of around 70 to 74 dollars
per barrel which of course is a positive
and higher than historical levels
additionally reduction in diesel export
duty is positive for the likes of
Reliance Industries because they have
higher diesel exports so expect Reliance
Industries to be in the green for today
ongc in all India could see some red but
overall it's not such a big negative for
these two stocks as well Kata thanks a
lot for that so another there will be a
couple of earnings that came in post
marketers
joins us with a quick analysis on that
survey
thanks so much for that so make skills
from ICICI Lombard the GDP I missed
estimates but the bad beat estimates
which was due to higher investment
income the gdpr which is the gross
direct premium income was up seven
percent at close to 4980 crores as
against the CNBC TV 18 poll of 5200 old
crores the net earned premium that was
up to 12 on a year-on-year basis the
combined ratio continues to be elevated
at 104 which was pretty much in line
with estimates and also what the
management has been guiding for a while
the company continues to guide a
combined ratio of 102 percent by fy25
which is a slight positive for the
company the claims ratio came in higher
than estimates that was driven by higher
claims ratio in the motor third-party
portfolio the management continues to
remain cautious in the motor business
given the competitive intensity that
combined with the regulatory environment
of Bringing Down the stake sale by the
promoter ICICI Bank continues to be an
overhang for the stock
next on my radar is start a coffee again
mix cues from there as well the revenue
was up 10 on a year on year basis this
was due to higher realization in the
eight o'clock and the instant coffee the
gross models and the ebitda margins were
impacted due to higher input costs and
also lower volumes the company saw gross
margin contraction of 500 basis points
the ebitda was lower by five percent and
the margins contracted by two percent
came in at 15 percent Pat was however
Higher by nine percent and that was
largely due to lower tax expenses
okay well uh Ruby thanks very much for
that Titan is the next one in focus
mangalam is standing by uh to tell his
wife hi hi so you know as far as Titan
is concerned there's an interesting note
that has come in from codec Securities
this morning and they say that their
industry interactions have suggested
that Titan has reduced franchisee
commissions from uh the first quarter of
this fiscal which is the quarter that
we're currently in uh so for stores
which are owned by the company but
operated by franchisees they've actually
reduced the commission by 50 to 60 basis
points from about five percent levels
and for stores which are owned and
operated by franchises which are L3
stores they will reduce the commissions
from 11 basis 11 percentage 10 to 11
Levels by about 100 basis points over
the next two years what this does is
improves their operating margins by
about 50 basis points over the next two
years and a large part of that would be
front-ended itself now they do not
expect this to impact their relationship
with franchisees or the motivation to
attract new franchises but remember this
is a rare and unprecedented event event
a positive one for their cost cutting
itself importantly we have written to uh
Titan to you know await confirmation
from them but what I understand from my
uh sources is that this is something
that the companies usually do primarily
to uh you know make it equal for all the
other franchisees uh during times of
disproportionate moves in you know the
sales that every franchise does so it
will not impact the motivation of all
the franchisees net net this should be a
positive for Titan
okay thanks a lot for that so positive
for Titan but let's go close to ekta
she's tracking a couple of stocks this
pyramid Pharma there's zeitus lives A
lot's happening here over to you
thanks for that well I'll start with
zydus life because they've received a
final approval from the usfda for
estradiol transdermal system which is
basically the generic version of
menostart transdermal system what it
does is that basically it's a batch that
you can put on your body which is used
to prevent post menopausal osteoporosis
the drug is going to be manufactured at
the company's Mariah facility Market
size is 1.9 million dollars Market size
is not that much but it's a complex drug
because it's a batch that you put on
your body and not just a pill that you
swallow so it is expected to be much
more complex in terms of manufacturing
and hence it could be a positive for
zydus Life simply because it's a complex
drug which has received approval from
the usfta pyramid the usft has concluded
the inspection of the company serious uh
sellers will manufacturing facility
they've received an establishment
inspection report indicating that the
facility is compliant hence we can
expect the stock to be in the green
okay all right uh thanks a lot for that
well uh Rima joins us to fill us in with
some more stocks that run the news Rima
morning
hi uh good morning so the first one on
my radar is e-clux where the company has
announced a new CEO Mr couple metha for
their UK subsidiary this is not the
overall CEO he's going to be the CEO of
the UK subsidy the UK arm of a clerks
and he's been hired from enforces where
he was the Executive Vice President
heading the BPM business and he's been
with uh you know Infosys for the last
two decades so it's another uh exit
coming in from uh in forces but a good
hire for e-clarks the other one is Bank
of India they held a board meeting
yesterday where the board has approved
uh that they will be raising funds to
the tune of six and a half thousand
crore rupees which is split wire four
and a half thousand of fresh Equity or
tier one bonds 81 and plus another 2000
crore via tier two bonds but I guess
this is a part of their General business
requirements and the third one on my
radar is soap distilleries where there
is some capacity expansion uh for br so
keep your right on some distilleries as
well back to you okay Everyone likes
enhanced capacity expansion for beer
right specifically thanks a lot for that
Rima but here's the quick recap of our
top stops with positive news flow uh
are names like Titan Reliance Industries
Peter malfama's diet is life E-class
services and Bank of India and some
distilleries while stocks with negative
news for this 1gcicsl Lombard and Tata
coffee but let's get a quick handle on
what's happening in the world of
Commodities Manisha Gupta is joining in
for all the action there Manisha hi good
morning
Sonia thank you for that I'll start with
the crude oil prices where we are
looking at some profit taking but it's
still holding above 80 dollars a barrel
so the Chinese economy growth in first
quarter clearly seems to be supportive
so does the fact that the Chinese
refineries processed record high crude
is the month of March markets also are
watching out as OPEC and allies start
reducing output from the month of May
and the user U.S food inventories also
have shown a decline on a week on week
basis all of these factors are
supportive but much higher support is
what we've seen in sense of metal prices
the decline in US Dollars strong Chinese
data has been supportive so we are
looking at Platinum Palladium gaining up
aluminum is trading at a six week highs
nickel copper zinc all of these Metals
gained anywhere between one to three
percent overnight and the Asian markets
have started on a positive note yet
again
okay thanks Manisha for that let's step
into a quick break there are plenty of
stocks actually to talk about so we'll
do one thing we'll get uh Sanjeev vasin
director IFL Securities will be joining
in for some fundamental stock analysis
we will also connect with subhadi Mitra
who's the executive director at lubama
institutional equities as a draft
National electricity plan expects to add
40 gigawatts of renewable energy
annually stay tuned for more on that
[Music]
foreign